<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>DECIDE Case Studies</title>
<link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/latest-content.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/latest-content.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<image>
<url>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/images/DECIDE_logo_RGB-1.png</url>
<title>DECIDE Case Studies</title>
<link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/latest-content.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.3.353</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Anonymisation</title>
  <dc:creator>Saba Noor, Miel Hostens, et al.</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/anonymisation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="anonymization" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="anonymization">Anonymization</h2>
<p>For privacy and confidentiality of sensitive information, we explain the anonymization technique for both R and Python code. For this, the SHA256 algorithm is used because it does not allow reverse engineering, and the sensitive information could not be linked back to the specific entity or individual.</p>
</section>
<section id="function-to-apply-sha-256-hashing-in-r" class="level1">
<h1>Function to apply SHA-256 hashing in R</h1>
<div class="cell">
<div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode r code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode r"><span id="cb1-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">require</span>(openssl)</span>
<span id="cb1-2"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Function to apply SHA-256 hashing</span></span>
<span id="cb1-3">sha256_hash <span class="ot" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&lt;-</span> <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">function</span>(data) {</span>
<span id="cb1-4">  openssl<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">::</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sha256</span>(data)</span>
<span id="cb1-5">}</span>
<span id="cb1-6"></span>
<span id="cb1-7">dplyr<span class="sc" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">::</span><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">mutate</span>(</span>
<span id="cb1-8">    <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">Filenumber=</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sha256_hash</span>(<span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">as.character</span>(Filenumber)),</span>
<span id="cb1-9">    <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">Samplenumber=</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sha256_hash</span>(<span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">as.character</span>(Samplenumber))</span>
<span id="cb1-10">)</span></code></pre></div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="function-to-apply-sha-256-hashing-in-r-1" class="level1">
<h1>Function to apply SHA-256 hashing in R</h1>
<div class="cell" data-python.reticulate="false">
<div class="sourceCode cell-code" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode python code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode python"><span id="cb2-1"><span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">!</span> pip install openpyxl</span>
<span id="cb2-2"><span class="im" style="color: #00769E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">import</span> hashlib</span>
<span id="cb2-3"></span>
<span id="cb2-4"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Generate anonymized values for file number and sample number</span></span>
<span id="cb2-5">FileNumber <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> hashlib.sha256(<span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">str</span>(FileNumber).encode()).hexdigest()</span>
<span id="cb2-6">SampleNumber <span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span> hashlib.sha256(SampleNumber).encode()).hexdigest()</span>
<span id="cb2-7"></span>
<span id="cb2-8"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># Add anonymized values to the RDF graph</span></span>
<span id="cb2-9">g.add((Sample, onto.hasFileNumber, Literal(FileNumber, datatype<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span>XSD.string)))</span>
<span id="cb2-10">g.add((Sample, onto.hasSampleNumber, Literal(SampleNumber, datatype<span class="op" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">=</span>XSD.string)))</span></code></pre></div>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Work Package 1</category>
  <category>Tutorial</category>
  <guid>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/anonymisation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/anonymisation.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cattle barometer</title>
  <dc:creator>Saba Noor, Jade Bokma, Bart Pardon, Miel Hostens, et al.</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/cattle-barometer.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="pasteurella-multocida" class="level1">
<h1>Pasteurella multocida</h1>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> P. multocida is an opportunistic bacterium and part of the common respiratory tract flora.¹ᐧ² Problems can occur during co-infection with viruses/Mycoplasma bovis or after extensive antimicrobial treatment.</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs:</strong> respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), septicemia</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample:</strong> respiratory tract (bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash), blood culture, peritoneal fluid, necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: culture and antimicrobial susceptibility testing, PCR** Carriers: yes</p>
<p><strong>Infection route:</strong> direct contact (nasal secretions), potentially close distance aerosol spread, potentially fomites</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines:</strong> Inactivated divalent vaccine (with Salmonella typhimurium) available in some EU countries</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Lima S.F., Teixeria A.G.V., Higgins C.H., Lima S.F., Bicalho R.C. 2016. The upper respiratory tract microbiome and its potential role in bovine respiratory disease and otitis media. Sci Rep 6.<br>
</li>
<li>Gaeta N.C., Lima S.F., Teixeria A.G., Ganda E.K., Oikonomou G., Gregory L., Bicalho R.C. 2017. Deciphering upper respiratory tract microbiota complexity in healthy calves and calves that develop respiratory disease using shotgun metagenomics. J Dairy Sci 100, 1445-1458.</li>
</ol>
<p>** Detection of an opportunistic pathogen by PCR confirms it present in the animal/herd, but does not evidence involvement in disease. P. multocida is that prevalent that PCR analysis is virtually useless.</p>
</section>
<section id="bovine-parainfluenza-3-virus" class="level1">
<h1>Bovine parainfluenza-3 virus</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Bovine parainfluenza-3 virus (bPI-3, also bovine respirovirus 3, 3 genotypes (A, B, C) genus: Respirovirus, family: Paramyxoviridae)</p>
<p><strong>Incubation period</strong>: 2-6 days</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> primary pathogen involved in bovine respiratory disease, predisposing for secondary bacterial infections</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), presumably mild as single infection</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (nasopharyngeal swab, bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash), necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> presumably not, subclinical infections likely most important for infection maintenance in the population</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: Direct: PCR, nanopore sequencing, antigen ELISA. Indirect: paired serum samples for antibody ELISA1 (interpretation may be hampered by maternal immunity)</p>
<p><strong>Infection route</strong>: aerosols, nasal secretion (direct contact), fomites</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines:</strong> Several multivalent vaccines (BRSV, BVD, M. haemolytica), inactivated or live-attenuated, parenteral or intranasal are available in Europe</p>
<p><strong>Eradication programs:</strong> no</p>
<p>* List incomplete, availability of commercial tests can differ between countries</p>
</section>
<section id="mannheimia-haemolytica" class="level1">
<h1>Mannheimia haemolytica</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Mannheimia haemolytica (member of the Pasteurellaceae family, two major genotypes (1 and 2))</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> M. haemolytica is an opportunistic bacterium and part of the common respiratory tract flora.¹ᐧ² Problems can occur during co-infection with viruses/Mycoplasma bovis and potentially also after breaches in the innate immunity of the respiratory tract by other factors. Outbreaks of virulent M. haemolytica strains in adult dairy cattle with acute mortality are described.³ᐧ⁴ &nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), septicemia</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash), peritoneal fluid, necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: culture and antimicrobial susceptibility testing; PCR**</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> yes</p>
<p><strong>Infection route:</strong> direct contact (nasal secretions), potentially close distance aerosol spread, potentially fomites</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines</strong>: both inactivated monovalent and multivalent vaccines (with H. somni, PI-3 or BRSV) are available in Europe.</p>
<p>1. Lima S.F., Teixeria A.G.V., Higgins C.H., Lima S.F., Bicalho R.C. 2016. The upper respiratory tract microbiome and its potential role in bovine respiratory disease and otitis media. Sci Rep 6.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>2. Gaeta N.C., Lima S.F., Teixeria A.G., Ganda E.K., Oikonomou G., Gregory L., Bicalho R.C. 2017. Deciphering upper respiratory tract microbiota complexity in healthy calves and calves that develop respiratory disease using shotgun metagenomics. J Dairy Sci 100, 1445-1458.</p>
<p>3. Dorso L., Rouault M., Barbotin C., Chartier C., Assié S. 2021. Infectious bovine respiratory disease in adult cattle: an extensive necropsic and etiological study. Animals (Basel) 11, 2280.</p>
<p>4. Mahu M., Valgaeren B., Pardon B., Deprez P., Haesebrouck F., Boyen F. 2015. Non-haemolytic Mannheimia haemolytica as a cause of pleuropneumonia and septicemia in a calf. Vet Microbiol 180, 157-160.</p>
<p>** Detection of an opportunistic pathogen by PCR confirms it present in the animal/herd, but does not evidence involvement in disease</p>
</section>
<section id="mycoplasma-bovis" class="level1">
<h1>Mycoplasma bovis</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Mycoplasma bovis</p>
<p><strong>Incubation period</strong>: 2-10 days</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> primary pathogen involved in bovine respiratory disease, mastitis, otitis and arthritis, often reported in co-infection with other viral or bacterial pathogens</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), ear drop, swollen joints, mastitis, seromas and rarer presentations¹</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (nasopharyngeal swab, bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash), milk, synovial fluid, necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> yes</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: Direct: culture (special media and CO2 rich incubation needed), PCR, MALDI-TOF MS, nanopore sequencing. Indirect: paired serum samples for antibody ELISA (interpretation may be hampered by maternal immunity)</p>
<p><strong>Infection route</strong>: nasal secretions (direct contact), colostrum, milk, semen, fomites¹ᐧ²&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines:</strong> Restrictedavailability of a monovalent registered vaccine and in some European countries autovaccines are allowed</p>
<p><strong>Eradication programs:</strong> voluntary program in Finland</p>
<p>1. Maunsell FP., Donovan G.A. 2009. Mycoplasma bovis infections in young calves. Vet Clin North Am Food Anim Pract 25, 139-177.</p>
<p>2. Haapala V., Pohjanvirta T., Vähänikkilä N., Halkilahti J., Simonen H., Pelkonen S., Soveri T., Simojoki H., Autio T. 2018. Semen as a source of Mycoplasma bovis mastitis in dairy herds. Vet Microbiol 216, 60-66.</p>
</section>
<section id="histophilus-somni" class="level1">
<h1>Histophilus somni</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Histophilus somni&nbsp; (member of the Pasteurellaceae family)</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> opportunistic pathogen involved in respiratory disease, septicemia, otitis, polyserositis and thrombotic meningoencephalitis-myelitis</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), central nervous signs (sleeper syndrome), swollen joints, ear drop and sudden death</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash)¹, blood culture, necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: PCR**, culture (CO2 rich incubation needed) and antimicrobial susceptibility testing</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> yes</p>
<p><strong>Infection route:</strong> direct contact (nasal secretions), urine, potentially fomites</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines:</strong> divalent inactivated vaccines (M. haemolytica, H. somni) are available in Europe</p>
<p>1. Van Driessche L., Valgaeren B.R., Gille L., Boyen F., Ducatelle R., Haesebrouck F., Deprez P., Pardon B. A deep nasopharyngeal swab versus nonendoscopic bronchoalveolar lavage for isolation of bacterial pathogens from preweaned calves with respiratory disease. J Vet Intern Med 31, 946-953.</p>
</section>
<section id="bovine-respiratory-syncytial-virus" class="level1">
<h1>Bovine respiratory syncytial virus</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Bovine respiratory syncytial virus (BRSV, also Bovine orthopneumovirus, multiple subtypes, genus: Orthopneumovirus, family: Pneumoviridae)</p>
<p><strong>Incubation period:</strong> 2-5 days</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance:</strong> primary pathogen involved in bovine respiratory disease, predisposing for secondary bacterial infections</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), potentially lethal as single agent</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (nasopharyngeal swab, bronchoalveolair lavage, transtracheal wash)¹ᐧ², necropsy</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: Direct: PCR, nanopore sequencing, antigen ELISA. Indirect: paired serum samples for antibody ELISA (interpretation may be hampered by maternal immunity)</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> persistent infection suggested but not evidenced, subclinical infections likely most important for infection maintenance in the population</p>
<p><strong>Infection route</strong>: airborne³, aerosol, nasal secretions (direct contact), fomites</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines:</strong> both monovalent vaccines and multivalent vaccines (combined with bPI-3, BVDV, M. haemolytica), inactivated or live attenuated, parenteral or intranasal are available in Europe</p>
<p><strong>Eradication programs:</strong> voluntary program in Norway</p>
<p>* List incomplete, availability of commercial tests can differ between countries</p>
<p>1. Doyle D., Credille B., Lehenbauer T.W., Berghaus R., Aly S.S., Champagne J., Blanchard P., Crossley B., Berghaus L., Cochran S., Woolums A. 2017. Agreement among 4 sampling methods to identify respiratory pathogens in dairy calves with acute bovine respiratory disease. J Vet Intern Med 31, 954-959.</p>
<p>2. Makoschey B., Berge A.C. 2021. Review on bovine respiratory syncytial virus and bovine parainfluenza – usual suspects in bovine respiratory disease – a narrative review. BMC Veterinary Research 17, 261.</p>
<p>3. Mars M.H., Bruschke C.J.M., Van Oirschot J.T. 1999. Airborne transmission of BHV1, BRSV, and BVDV among cattle is possible under experimental conditions. Vet Microbiol 66, 197-207.</p>
</section>
<section id="bovine-coronavirus" class="level1">
<h1>Bovine coronavirus</h1>
<p><strong>Pathogen:</strong> Bovine coronavirus (BCoV, genus: Betacoronavirus, family: Coronaviridae)</p>
<p><strong>Incubation period:</strong> 1-7 days</p>
<p><strong>Clinical relevance</strong>: primary pathogen involved in bovine respiratory disease¹, calf diarrhea and winter dysentery², predisposing for secondary bacterial infections</p>
<p><strong>Clinical signs</strong>: respiratory disease (coughing, nasal discharge, dyspnea, fever), calf diarrhea, winter dysentery (cows)</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic sample</strong>: respiratory tract (nasopharyngeal swab, bronchoalveolar lavage, transtracheal wash)³, necropsy, feces</p>
<p><strong>Diagnostic test</strong>*: Direct: PCR, nanopore sequencing, antigen ELISA. Indirect: paired serum samples for antibody ELISA4 (interpretation may be hampered by maternal immunity)</p>
<p><strong>Infection route</strong>: aerosols, nasal secretions (direct contact), feces, fomites</p>
<p><strong>Carriers:</strong> limited evidence, differentiation from prolonged shedding difficult, subclinical infections likely most important for infection maintenance in the population</p>
<p><strong>Vaccines</strong>: multivalent vaccines containing inactivated bovine coronavirus (combined with bovine rotavirus and Enterotoxic Escherichia coli) next to other intestinal pathogens intended for dams are registered for neonatal calf diarrhea in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>Eradication programs:</strong> voluntary program in Norway</p>
<p>* List incomplete, availability of commercial tests can differ between countries</p>
<p>¹&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Decaro N., Campolo M., Desario C., Cirone F., D’abramo M., Lorusso E., Greco G., Mari V., Colaianni M.L., Elia G., Martella V., Buonavoglia C. 2008. Respiratory disease associated with bovine coronavirus infection in cattle herds in Southern Italy. J Vet Diagn Invest 20, 28-32.</p>
<p>²&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Boileau M.J., Kapil S.2010. Bovine coronavirus associated syndromes. Vet Clin north Am Food Anim Pract 26, 123-146.</p>
<p>³&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Doyle D., Credille B., Lehenbauer T.W., Berghaus R., Aly S.S., Champagne J., Blanchard P., Crossley B., Berghaus L., Cochran S., Woolums A. 2017. Agreement among 4 sampling methods to identify respiratory pathogens in dairy calves with acute bovine respiratory disease. J Vet Intern Med 31, 954-959</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Cattle</category>
  <category>Work Package 1</category>
  <category>Use case</category>
  <guid>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/cattle-barometer.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/cattle-barometer-tutorial.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ontology</title>
  <dc:creator>Saba Noor, Miel Hostens, et al.</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="system-model" class="level1">
<h1>System Model</h1>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 1: Non-Ontology Based (Traditional One) generic framework of Farm Animal Data Management</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Non-ontology-based systems require rewriting the cleaning code each time new data arrives, making it time-consuming and tedious. These systems lack interoperability, flexibility, reusability, and accessibility, posing limitations in data integration, handling, and adaptability.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-2.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 2: Ontology-Driven Knowledge-based framework of Farm Animal Data Management (ODKFADM)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>In this use case, we utilize the ODKFADM framework to evaluate cattle-related data (DGZ), It involves collecting raw data from different data sources i.e.&nbsp;DGZ, and including information about farm identification, geo-location, infectious diseases, PCR, and bacterial culture results. This framework enables effective analysis of the data, leading to insights into cattle health</p>
<section id="step-1-data-acquisition-and-rdf-conversions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-1-data-acquisition-and-rdf-conversions">Step 1: Data Acquisition and RDF conversions</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-3.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 3: Data Acquisition and RDF Conversions</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>In Figure 3, we read heterogeneous raw data using pandas, and R data frames, and then convert them into RDF format.</p>
</section>
<section id="step-2-species-specific-ontology-lho" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-2-species-specific-ontology-lho">Step 2: Species-Specific Ontology (LHO)</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-4.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 4: Graphical Representation of LHO</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="step-3-rdf-data-and-ontology-integration-mapping" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-3-rdf-data-and-ontology-integration-mapping">Step 3: RDF Data and Ontology Integration (Mapping)</h2>
<p>In this step we map the RDF data with LHO which enhances the reasoning and query capabilites</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-5.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 5: RDF and Ontology Integration (Mapping)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<pre><code></code></pre>
</section>
<section id="step-4-knowledge-graph-ontology-update" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-4-knowledge-graph-ontology-update">Step 4: Knowledge graph (Ontology Update)</h2>
<p>Resulted into a knowledge graph</p>
</section>
<section id="step-5-reasoning-and-query" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-5-reasoning-and-query">Step 5: Reasoning and Query</h2>
<p>Figure 6 and 7 shows Query and query results that Filtering positive PathogenResults and MycoplasmaResults associated with CattleSample</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-6.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 6: Filtering positive PathogenResults and MycoplasmaResults associated with CattleSample</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies-figure-7.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure 7: Query result</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="step-6-visualization-and-analysis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="step-6-visualization-and-analysis">Step 6: Visualization and Analysis</h2>
<p>We choose Tableau for the visualization method. It provides meaningful insights to explore the knowledge graph. For this, we need a working ODBC connection to a Virtuoso Instance and ODBC or JDBC Compliant version of Tableau or Tableau Server. For ODBC connection to virtuoso, the link is: <a href="https://medium.com/virtuoso-blog/virtuoso-tableau-sparql-f9411852a87d">Visualizing SPARQL Results in Tableau | by Daniel Heward-Mills | OpenLink Virtuoso Weblog | Medium</a></p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Work package 1</category>
  <category>Ontology building</category>
  <category>Tutorial</category>
  <guid>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/ontologies.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Poultry Barometer</title>
  <dc:creator>Yara Slegers, Sjaak de Wit, Miel Hostens, et al.</dc:creator>
  <link>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/poultry-barometer.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="aim" class="level1">
<h1>Aim</h1>
<p>The aim of the “Poultry Barometer” is to provide insight into the most prevalent Infectious Bronchitis Virus (IBV) strains in broiler chickens within specific regions and periods.</p>
</section>
<section id="background" class="level1">
<h1>Background</h1>
<p>IBV causes infectious bronchitis (IB) in poultry. An infection can lead to respiratory signs, drop in production, and kidney damage. In the Netherlands, broilers are often vaccinated against IBV to limit the impact of disease. However, vaccines do not protect against all IBV strains, and new strain are regularly discovered. Insights into the most prevalent strains can help to better protect broiler flocks against IBV.</p>
<p>For more information on IBV, visit the <a href="https://www.gdanimalhealth.com/Disease-control/Animal-diseases/Infectious-Bronchitis">GD website</a></p>
</section>
<section id="data" class="level1">
<h1>Data</h1>
<p>Currently, the dashboard only includes data from the Netherlands, provided by Royal GD. Royal GD performs PCR tests on submitted material to detect IBV. If the virus is detected, sequencing will determine the specific IBV genotype.</p>
<p>Only anonymous data is used to create the dashboard. After linking a farm to the correct province, farm identification is removed from the data. The dashboard shows only aggregated data.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Poultry</category>
  <category>Work Package 1</category>
  <category>Use case</category>
  <guid>https://github.com/decide-project-eu/case-studies-website/tutorials/poultry-barometer.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
